Guide to the Oliver P. Merriman Scrapbook Collection, 1825-1942 CTC.1964.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Coded Scrapbooks, 1866-1941; IV.
  - Scrapbook Davis - Harry Davis Productions, 1896-1940; pages 1-94 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Liberty Hall, 1901; page 61
    - The New Stock Company, 1901-1902
    - Davis Article, 1940; pages 91-94
  - Scrapbook STO1 - Pittsburgh Stock and Repertory Companies, 1896-1941; pages 1-82 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
  - Scrapbook STO2 - Pittsburgh Stock and Repertory Companies, 1902-1941; pages 1-124 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
  - Scrapbook GO - Grand Opera in Pittsburgh, 1866-1940; pages 1-108 (Box 27, Folder 7-8)
  - Scrapbook VAR (no. 1) - Variety Theatre in Pittsburgh, 1879-1940; pages 1-142 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
    - Varieties Theatre, 1937; pages 1-5
    - Tivoli Garden, 1872-1881; pages 7-17
    - Trimble's Varieties Theatre, page 19
    - Harry Williams Academy, 1893; page 27
    - Various Vaudeville Programs, 1879-1940; pages 21-25, 29-142
  - Scrapbook VAR (no. 2) - Variety Theatre in Pittsburgh, 1898-1937; pages 1-80 (Box 28, Folder 3-4)
    - The Nixon, 1907; page 1
    - The Gayety, 1907-1920; pages 3-51
    - Various Programs, 1898-1937; pages 53-80
  - Scrapbook VAUD GOH - Vaudeville at Pittsburgh's Grand Opera House, 1906-1940; pages 1-126 (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
- Scrapbook Stg. Stars - Stage and Its Stars, Past and Present, 1887; V.
  This series contains several folder of photogravure images of theatre performers. All the images are from the work The Stage and it's Stars. The book has been disbound. The full title of the book is The stage and its stars past and present: a gallery of dramatic illustration and critical biographies of distinguished English and American actors from the time of Shakespeare till to-day, edited by Howard Paul and George Gebbie. Please note that the Curtis Collection has another copy of this work still in its original binding.
  - Volume 1, 1887; V.; pages 1-102 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Volume 2, 1887; pages 1-98 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Volume 3, 1887; pages 1-208 (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
  - Volume 4, 1887; pages 1-208 (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
- Obituary Scrapbooks - "Final Curtain", 1876-1941; VI.
  This segment of the scrapbook collection contains three volumes of obituary scrapbooks. Included with the clipped obituaries, there are occasional photos, correspondence, and autographs. There is a small amount of non theatre or performing arts individuals represented, mostly political figures.
  - 52A - Obituaries A-L, 1876-1936; pages 1-72 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - 52A - Obituaries M-Z, 1899-1935; pages 73-124 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - 52B (vol.2), 1895-1941 (Box 29, Folder 7-8)
  - 52C (vol. 3), 1894-1941; pages 1-127 (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
- Addenda Items List, 1880-1942; VII. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  This small grouping of materials never found their place in Merriman's scrapbook scheme. Most of the materials are from the 1940s, so he may have passed away before he could create a proper section for them. These materials are all housed in one folder and are grouped into five subseries - Programs, Photographs and Other Images, Newspaper Clippings, and materials related to Thomas Kirk, a Pittsburgh theatre manager. Finally, there is one box of a representative sample of scrapbook bindings.
  - Programs, 1880-1942; 1.
    - Kind to a Fault and Tom Cobb - Clapham Bicycle Club London's Surry Masonic Hall, December 12, 1883
    - The Belle of New York - Pittsburgh's Alvin Theatre, January 16, 1899
    - Impulse - St. James's Theatre
    - Comrades and The Happy Return - London's Court Theatre, 1883
    - Lady Clare - London's Royal Globe Theatre, 1883
    - Takings it Easy!, Dearer than Life, Mr. Guffin's Elopement - London's Toole's Theatre, 1883
    - Chimes of Normandy - Pittsburgh Opera Company at the Pitt Theatre, June 26, 1913
    - Stephen C. Foster Serenaders, The Bells, The Hole in the Wall, La Schelle Perileuse, and The Go-nod Club - Pittsburgh Opera House, 1880
    - Coaina - Showalter's Opera Hose, December 25, 1884
    - Excelsior, Jr. - Rice's Burlesque Company, November 23, 1896
    - Secret Service
    - The Girl from Paris - Rice's Burlesque Company
    - Lost, Strayed or Stolen, January 3, 1897
    - Brian Boru
    - Never Again, March 6, 1897
    - My Friend from India
    - Half A King, April 5, 1897
    - The Mandarin, April 19, 1897
    - Watch on the Rhine - Pittsburgh's Nixon Theatre, April 13, 1942
    - The Man Who Remembered - Pittsburgh's Davis Theater, December 14, 1925
  - Photographs and Other Images, 2.
    - James N. McGrath, June 26, 1937
      James N McGrath, Jr. was a stage manager for Pittsburgh's Syria Mosque and Alvin Theatre. This photo is autographed.
    - Macready as Virginus, Macbeth
    - The Franklin Statue
    - James. E. Murdoch
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1920-1942; 3.
    - George S. Kaufman and George S. Kaufmann, 1938
    - Rebirth of Vaudeville - New York Times Magazine, April 19, 1942
    - Personality Portraits - Helen Hayes
    - A. Davis, Collector of Stage Photos - New York Times, April 23, 1942
    - The Drama - by Arthur Hornblow Theatre Magazine, May 1920
    - Spring Again - Review, 1941
    - C(Ricket) Aubrey Smith - New York Times, November 30, 1941
    - Ethel and Diana Barrymore, 1940-1941
    - Nixon Gets 'Watch on the Rhine', 1942
    - National Geographic Magazine - Circus articles, October 1931
  - Thomas Kirk, 1912-1919; 4.
    Thomas Frances Kirk, Jr. was the manager of Pittsburgh's Nixon Theatre from 1901-1916.
    - Souvenir Program - Testimonial to Thomas Francis Kirk, Jr., Nov. 23, 1917
    - Thomas Kirk - Photograph
    - T.G. Kirk Jr. Dies After Long Illness, October 17, 1919
    - Thos. F. Kirk, Sr.
    - Thomas Kirk - Nixon Magazine, May 5, 1912
  - Representative scrapbook covers, 5. (Box 31)